A Guide to the Papers of Woodrow Wilson, 1184-1924
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Woodrow Wilson 1884-1924
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
: Multiple numbers
The collection consists of 213 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired by gift and purchase.
Biographical/Historical Information
Twenty-Eighth President, 1913-1921. Born: December 28, 1856 in Staunton, Virginia. Died: February 3, 1924 in Washington D.C. Married to Ellen Louise Axson Wilson and to Edith Bolling Galt Wilson.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of letters by Wilson, chiefly to various friends and politicians. The collection also includes photographs of Wilson as Governor of New Jersey and President of the United States.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Woodrow Wilson to John B. Minor 1884 April 29, ALS (Box 1)
    #3750
  - Woodrow Wilson to John B. Minor 1884 May 2, ALS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to John B. Minor 1886 December 2, ALS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to John B. Minor 1886 December 20, ALS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to "My precious father" [Joseph Ruggles Wilson] 1888 December 16, ALS (facsimile) (Box 1)
    #9725
  - Woodrow Wilson to Charles [W.] [Kent] 1896 November 11, ALS (Box 1)
    #3847
  - Woodrow Wilson to Professor W. H. Perkinson 1898 April 1, ALS (Box 1)
    #11227
  - Woodrow Wilson to Robert Lee Powers 1898 November 3, ALS (Box 1)
    #11002
  - Woodrow Wilson to Gordon M. Buck 1898 December 20, ALS (Box 1)
    #8142
  - Woodrow Wilson to Mr. Lucian H. Cocke 1901 January 10, TLS (Box 1)
    #762
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1903 January 29, TLS (Box 1)
    #1001
  - Woodrow Wilson to John S. Patton 1903 June 6, TLS (Box 1)
    #8613
  - Woodrow Wilson to Mrs. William Hoyt King 1904 October 20, TLS (Box 1)
    #752
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1904 October 26, TLS (Box 1)
    RG-2/1/2.472I
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1906 April 19, TLS (Box 1)
    #2672
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 197 December 16, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Marion J. Verdery 1910 September 16, TLS (Box 1)
    #6757-a
  - Woodrow Wilson to Raleigh C. Minor 1910 November 12, TLS (Box 1)
    #5660-d
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1910 November 24, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Charles Alphonso Smith 1911 January 3, TLS (Box 1)
    #924
  - Woodrow Wilson to P. B. Barringer 1911 January 10, TLS (Box 1)
    #5858-j
  - Woodrow Wilson to Professor Minor 1911 March 27, TLS (Box 1)
    #5660
  - Woodrow Wilson to Philip A. Bruce 1911 April 18, TLS (Box 1)
    #2889
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1911 November 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1911 December 4, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Paul Barringer 1911 December 4, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1912 February 27, TLS (Box 1)
    #2913
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1912 April 11, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Dr. H. G. Norton 1912 May 21, TLS (Box 1)
    #6359
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1912 June 6, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1912 January 16, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wislon to Philip A. Bruce 1912 July 23, TL (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1912 August 6, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1912 August 10, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Milt Goodkind 1912 October 16, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Milt Goodkind 1912 October 21, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1912 October 25, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Milt Goodkind 1912 December 11, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1912 December 23, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1913 January 1, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1913 January 7, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1913 February 3, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1913 February 5, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1913 February 10, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1913 February 26, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1913 Mar 17, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1913 April 14, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1913 May 8, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Ernest Baynes 1913 May 20, TLS (Box 1)
    #1125
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1913 June 20, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1913 January 9, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1913 July 29, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1913 August 26, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1913 September 26, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to South Trimble 1913 November 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1914 January 30, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1914 March 27, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1914 April 9, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1914 May 26, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to C. C. Caslin 1914 July 7, TLS (Box 1)
    #5000
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1914 September 8, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1914 October 23, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to George Howe 1914 November 8, TLS (Box 1)
    #6757
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1914 December 4, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Raleigh C. Minor 1915 January 5, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1915 March 1, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to W.E. Pulsifer 1915 May 14, TLS (Box 1)
    #6757-b
  - Woodrow Wilson appointment of Edwin A. Alderman 1915 June 1, DS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to W. E. Pulsifer 1915 June 23, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Emily G. Balch 1915 August 2, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1915 October 13, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1915 October 29, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1916 January 13, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1916 January 16, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1916 April 25, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1916 June 19, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1916 September 20, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Thomas S. Martin 1916 November 17, TLS (Box 1)
    #1502
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1916 December 2, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Rosewell Page 1916 December 5, TLS (Box 1)
    #8641
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1917 January 12, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1917 January 25, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1917 January 30, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Rev. Dr. Frank G. Porter 1917 March 30, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1917 May 4, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1918 January 14, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Mrs. Kenneth Brown 1918 February 7, TLS (Box 1)
    #9732
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edward R. Stettinius 1918 April 12, TLS (Box 1)
    #2723
  - Woodrow Wilson to Collins Denny 1918 April 19, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1918 April 21, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1918 June 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1918 November 13, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Josephus Daniels 1918 November 27, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1919 February 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1919 February 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1919 August 8, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1919 August 14, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Thomas Walker Page 1920 January 15, TLS (Box 1)
    #12777
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1920 January 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1920 February 4, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to the President and Faculty, University of Virginia 1920 March 6, TLS (Box 1)
    #2649
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1920 March 11, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1920 March 20, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1920 May 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Messrs. D. C. Heath & Co. 1920 July 8, TLS (Box 1)
    #6393
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1920 October 22, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Miss Betty Cocke 1920 November 26, TLS (Box 1)
    #2433-ad, -ae
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1920 December 11, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Thomas Walker Page 1921 January 15, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1921 February 5, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to J. Rives Childs 1921 March 3, TLS (Box 1)
    #9256-f
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1921 April 30, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1921 September 15, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1921 December 24, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Mr. McLane Tilton 1921 December 25, TLS (Box 1)
    #358
  - Woodrow Wilson to Miss Betty Cocke 1921 December 31, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Edwin A. Alderman 1922 February 18, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Mr. McLane Tilton 1922 February 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1922 May 21, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1922 June 18, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Thomas Nelson Page 1922 October 28, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Miss Betty Cocke 1922 November 13, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1922 December 29, TLS (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson to Carter Glass 1923 November 12, TLS (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Photograph of Woodrow Wilson n.d. (Box 2)
    Inscribed by Wilson. #7690-ah
  - Photograph of Woodrow Wilson n.d. (Box 2)
    Inscribed by Wilson. #38-192-a
  - Governor Woodrow Wilson (left) and the man who was responsible for his getting the Presidential nomination, Wm. F. McCoombs. n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 1. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson and Mayor Mitchell of New York n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 2. (#38-192)
  - Governor Wilson and Governor Harmon of Ohio n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 3. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson and President Poincaré of France. Arrival at Paris n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 4. (#38-192)
  - President and Mrs. Wilson at the inauguration of the airplane mail. Postmaster Merrit L. Chance of Washington and Postmaster General Burleson also at the ceremony n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 5. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson with his class at Yale-Princeton baseball game n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 6. (#38-192)
  - President and Mrs. Wilson reviewing Red Cross parade n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 7. (#38-192)
  - Woodrow Wilson at notification meeting at Shadow Lawn n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 8. (#38-192)
  - Woodrow Wilson and Thomas R. Marshall n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 9. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson and his secretary Joseph P. Tumulty n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 10. (#38-192)
  - Group picture, showing left to right: Senator Tillman, Governor Osborne, J.B. Sanford, P.L. Hall, Governor Wilson, Norman E. Mack, Mr. Saulsburg, Mr. Davies, Mr. Mountcastle n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 11. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson opening second baseball game of World Series n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 12. (#38-192)
  - Champ Clark and Governor Wilson at Sea Girt, N.J. n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 13. (#38-192)
  - Governor Wilson and W.G. McAdoo (left) n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 14. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson leaving Princeton for Washington n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 15. (#38-192)
  - U.S. Peace Conference officials in conference at Hotel Crillon, Paris, December 19, 1918, left to right, Col. E.W. House, Mr. Robert Lansing, Secretary of State, President Wilson, Henry White, former U.S. ambassador to France, General Tasker H. Bliss n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 16. (#38-192)
  - Woodrow Wilson and his family n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 17. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson and the King of Italy. Acknowledging welcome on arrival at railroad station n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 18. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson in conference n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 19. (#38-192)
  - Mayor and Corporation of Dover, England receiving President Wilson after his arrival in England. The President is accompanied by the Duke of Connaught. Lord Reading is also in the right of picture. n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 20. (#38-192)
  - Advisory Committee of Representative Producers of Farm Products and Live Stock, formed by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Food Administration during the World War, calling on President Wilson n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 21. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson and Mrs. Townsley. Mrs. Wilson and General Townsley n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 22. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson discussing the high cost of living with Governor Sproul of Pennsylvania. Governor Cooper of South Carolina, center. n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 23. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson at his desk n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 24. (#38-192)
  - The arrival of President Wilson at Union Station, Washington, D.C., after his tour in the interest of the League of Nations n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 25. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson delivering his inaugural address n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 26. (#38-192)
  - President and Mrs. Wilson n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 27. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson at World Series baseball game, Washington, D.C. n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 28. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson and former President Taft n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 29. (#38-192)
  - On the bridge of the U.S.S. George Washington, en route to England, left to right, Mrs. Robert Lansing, Mrs. Wilson, President Wilson, Dr. Grayson n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 30. (#38-192)
  - President and Mrs. Wilson at baseball game, Washington, D.C. n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 31. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson and Captain McCauley on the bridge of the U.S.S. George Washington n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 32. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson (a later picture) n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 33. (#38-192)
  - Governor Mann of Virginia, President Wilson, Governor Pothier of Rhode Island at Sea Girt, N.J. n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 34. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson and General Pershing in France, standing at salute while the national anthem is being played n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 35. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson, a portrait study n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 36. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson leaving presidential mansion for Armistice Day celebration n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 37. (#38-192)
  - Conference of Governors and Attorneys General of seven states, with President Wilson and U.S. Attorney General Palmer, in Washington, D.C. to discuss means of cooperating with federal agencies to combat the high cost of living. n.d. (Box 2)
    Front row: Governor W.C. Sproul, Pennsylvania; Attorney General A. Mitchell Palmer; President Wilson; Governor F.D. Gardner, Missouri. Others, left to right: Brigadier General Barry of Pennsylvania; Governor C.F. Milliken, Maine; Governor R.W. Cooper, South Carolina; Governor Thomas E. Campbell, Arizona; Attorney General John T. Gose, Missouri; Governor A.A. Burnquist, Minnesota; Secretary of Governors Conference, M.E. Riley; Secretary to Governor Sproul, Harry S. McDevitt; Lieutenant Governor McDowell, Montana. Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 38. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson at ship launching n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 39. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson at Bureau of Printing, Washington, D.C. n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 40. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson, a portrait study n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 41. (#38-192)
  - President Wilson, delivering inaugural address n.d. (Box 2)
    Forms part of the G.E. Thompson Woodrow Wilson Photograph Collection. Mounted on linen and hinged. 42. (#38-192)
  - Woodrow Wilson, made during Peace Conference n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyright by Harris & Ewing" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 1. (#5220)
  - President and Mrs. Wilson arriving for the opening meeting of the Peace Conference in Paris n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 2. (#5220)
  - Wilson and Taft. First inaguration of Mr. Wilson. Made at White House n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 3. (#5220)
  - Joseph Tumulty, former secretary to Mr. Wilson, arriving at the Wilson house this morning. n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 4. (#5220)
  - Showing Woodrow Wilson at window of his house last Armistice Day, when 20,000 people had their last look at him n.d. (Box 2)
    "Photo by Pacific & Atlantic Photos, Inc." From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 5. (#5220)
  - Wilson on his way to Capital for first inauguration in 1913 riding with Taft n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 6. (#5220)
  - "There is no hope" Dr. Grayson's message to waiting newspaper men n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 7. (#5220)
  - Vance McCormick, former chairman of the Democratic National Committee talking with newspaper men at the Wilson house n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 8. (#5220)
  - Wilson and aides at White House, first inauguration n.d. (Box 2)
    Two copies. "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 9. (#5220)
  - Second inauguration? n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 10. (#5220)
  - Wilson at Paris Peace Conference? n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyright by Underwood & Underwood" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 11. (#5220)
  - President and Mrs. Wilson during 2nd inaugural parade n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 12. (#5220)
  - President and Mrs. Wilson at burial of unknown soldier n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 13. (#5220)
  - Wilson, Harding, Cannon, Knox n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 14. (#5220)
  - Wilson taking oath of office, first inauguration n.d. (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 15 (#5220)
  - President Wilson addressing Congress on break with Germany n.d. (Box 2)
    A scene in the House chamber as President Wilson delivered his reply to the German U-boat warning today (Feb.3, 1917). Photo by Central News Photo Service. From the Papers of Douglas Southall Freeman. 16. (#5220)
  - Photographs of Woodrow Wilson at the Paris peace conference 1919, 29 photographs (b.& w.) (Box 2)
    United States Army Signal Corps. (#9005)
  - Woodrow Wilson addressing the Senate n.d. (Box 2)
    From the Papers of William Jett Lauck (#4742)
  - Woodrow Wilson at Warren G. Harding's funeral 1923 (Box 2)
    "Copyrighted National Photo" From the Papers of Edward L. Stone (#4742)